LÍVIA ALMEIDA

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

www.livia.tech





ABOUT

My goal is to build products that solve its users' problems while providing a great usability. I like to work closely with the design team, in highly collaborative environments.

My main interests are code architecture and code quality, design systems, and CSS animations. I am proficient in both JavaScript and TypeScript, having worked mainly with the frameworks Angular and Vue.



C / C++

C#

CSS

JavaScript

Python

SQL

HTML

TypeScript



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ECOSIA

(apr 2021 - present)

(aug 2020 - present)

QUESTRADE

SYMBAROS

(june 2020 - dec 2020)

BLIP.AI

(TAKE.BLIP)

(jun 2019 - apr 2020)

BLIP.AI

(TAKE.BLIP)

(jan 2018 - may 2019)

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Working as a freelancer front-end engineer for the search engine that plants trees. Using frameworks Vue.JS and Nuxt with HTML and SCSS.

PARTNER / CONSULTANT

Working as a front-end architect consultant for a platform specialized in renting commercial spaces. Setting up architecture and building website in Vue.JS.

FRONT-END ENGINEER

Worked as a front-end engineer for a trading platform using Angular8+, TypeScript, and SCSS.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Worked as a full stack developer using AngularJS and Vue.JS for front-end, .NET core for back-end, and occasionally Python for NLP models analysis.

DEVELOPMENT INTERNSHIP

Worked as a front-end intern in the chatbot building platform BLiP.ai using frameworks AngularJS and Vue.JS, provided solutions on Artificial Intelligence using Python, and analyzed NLP models based on intents and entities.



EDUCATION

UNIVERSIDADE FEDERAL DE MINAS GERAIS

ends in dec 2021

COMPUTER SCIENCE

This bachelor degree aims to train professionals focused on the development of computer systems, notably programming systems (software).



SQ-LEARN www.sqlearn.net

DATABASE QUERY LEARNING

The goal of sq-learn is to help everyone who wants to learn queries in SQL by having an intuitive interface to visualize the database.



TALKS

THE

DEVELOPER'S CONFERENCE

Jun 14th 2019

WORD EMBEDDING AND APPLICATION

How to develop an application to solve a recurring Natural Language Processing problem using the Word Embedding algorithm? We are going to explore the spell cherk task

DEVELOPER CIRCLE

Feb 19th 2019

HOW TO LEARN USING TEXT?

To use words in mathematical models, we rely on transforming them into some form of numerical representation. One of many algorithms that perform such task is the Word Embedding.



LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

Proficiency: fluent reading, fluent writing, fluent speech IELTS 7.5 (03/06/2021)

♦ FRENCH

Proficiency: intermediate reading, basic writing, basic speech Level A1.3



